SEBASTIAAN SCHIMMEL

Full Stack Developer

Address

H.J.P. Fesevurstraat 9 **Skype**: sebastiaan_schimmel 1e Verdieping | Kamer 53 **Phone**: +3185 303 3586

7415 CM Deventer Email: s.schimmel@675internet.nl
The Netherlands Website: www.675internet.nl

I'm an experienced software development professional who turns ideas into reality by writing code for the web and the internet of things.

Starting projects from scratch, working on an architecture, picking the right technology stack and setting-up the infrastructure isn't for everyone. It is however where I excel at. I work with or as the product owner to turn ideas into a workable backlog, setup the software development process and tools like continues integration and write the first version of your code to get your idea of the ground quickly without compromising on quality.

SKILLS OVERVIEW

Languages

Node.JS, PHP, Go, HTML, CSS, Javascript

Frameworks

Sails.JS, Express, Meteor, Laravel, ¡Query, Bootstrap, Materialize

Software

MySQL, Elasticsearch, Neo4J, Git, NGINX, Apache, Docker, Mesosphere, Android Studio, Redis, OSX, Linux



WORK EXPERIENCE

EasyOptimize (RWE) Full Stack Developer

Mar 2016 – Present

easyOptimize (part of RWE) is developing a new smart energy solution to face the challenges of distributed energy production by creating communities of electricity producers and consumers. For this a new software and hardware platform is developed for which I've setup the technical architecture and infrastructure as well as developing the platform in Node.JS, Go and some PHP.

Tech stack: Node.JS, PHP, Go, Electron, MySQL, Neo4J, Elasticsearch

AcouTronics

Architect / Consultant

Jan 2016 – Feb 2016

AcouTronics needed advice on the systems architecture for a new to develop data reporting application. After collecting their functional requirements, I wrote the technical design for this application

Enrise

Freelance Developer

Nov 2015 – Jan 2016

For Enrise I worked on API and ElasticSearch plugin development using Node.JS for the API and Java for the Elasticsearch plugin. I delivered several new API's and extended existing ones. The ElasticSearch plugin that I extended is used to run custom calculations on search results.

Enrise uses Scrum and works according to Test Driven Development.

Tech stack: Node.JS, Elasticsearch, Java, Grunt, Mocha, Sinon, Chai, Restify

Hugo Dec 2014 – Oct 2015

Co-founder

As co-founder I designed and developed the Hugo platform using Node.JS, PHP and Meteor with Java for the <u>Hugo Encounters</u> Android app. The platform is designed in a micro services architecture with the services running in Docker containers. I used Amazon Web Services with Mesosphere (Mesos + Marathon) for the DCOS to create a highly flexible and scalable platform. At Hugo I worked with one remote developer. Total team size 5 employees and 3 founders.

Centrally in the Hugo platform is the REST API written in Node.JS using Sails.JS for the framework. The API communicates with the MySQL database and the other services. The website and customer backoffice are written in PHP using the Laravel framework. Experiences are collected using a Meteor web application. Background workers written in PHP with Laravel handle all background related tasks like sending email and calculating scores. These workers listen for jobs on a SQS queue.

Tech stack: PHP, Node.JS, Meteor, MySQL, Android, Java, Redis, Elasticsearch, Docker, Mesosphere (Mesos + Marathon), Git, SailsJS, Laravel, HTML, CSS, Javascript, jQuery, Bootstrap, NGINX, Amazon Web Services (AWS), SQS, S3, EC2, RDS, Cloudfront, Route53, Mandrill, API, REST, Facebook API, JSON. Complete stack on <u>stackshare</u>.

Urban Farm

Founder

Apr 2013 – present

Born out of a hobby for urban farming I started a <u>webshop</u> supplying Dutch consumers with urban farming supplies. The store is build using Magento, PHP, MySQL and a customized template. I maintain my own server hosting the store.

Tech stack: PHP, MySQL, Magento, HTML, CSS, Javascript

Paylogic International

Product Manager

Nov 2013 - Oct 2014

As product manager I was responsible for the on-/offline sales channels and Paylogic's entrance management solution. I worked with three development teams as a Scrum Product Owner.

During my time at Paylogic I developed and launched a new mobile friendly version of their online ticket shop used by 3 million customers per year, greatly improved their point of sale solution for door sales and delivered the first version of the open API.

Divehub

Founder

Jan 2013 – Nov 2013

The idea behind <u>Divehub</u> is to enable scuba divers to find the best places to dive and easily book their travel arrangements. While the general travel industry has moved to direct packaging where travellers design their own travel experience instead of relying on ready-made packages the scuba travel industry is still selling these packages. I set out to change that with Divehub.

Scuba divers keep track of their dives in a logbook that's still mostly done on paper. Paper logbooks get lost, can be forgotten and don't allow to share dive experiences easily. Divehub enables divers to keep track of their dives online and using an Android app. Dives are synced between devices and online and are always available and shared easily.

Tech stack: PHP, MySQL, Android (Java), HTML, CSS, LESS, Javascript, jQuery, API, REST, Laravel, Amazon Web Services, Flickr API, Facebook API, JSON.

Raet

Productverantwoordelijke

Jun 2011 – Feb 2013

The position of Productverantwoordelijke combines the roles of Product Manager and Unit Manager. I lead the development efforts of the Raet Talent Management System. The SaaS software was developed by three teams of which two were offshore in India in .Net on the Microsoft Azure platform.

I finished the migration from PHP to .Net and added several new features, setup partnerships with other software vendors and lead the customer focus groups. The software was developed using Scrum.

Raet

Productverantwoordelijke

Nov 2010 - Jun 2011

The position of Productverantwoordelijke combines the roles of Product Manager and Unit Manager. I lead the development efforts for the HR Core system for the forprofit market. Total team size was 21 in-house software engineers, analysts and testers.

Responsibilities included user research, roadmap creation, backlog management, presales activities, partnerships and customer relationship management.

Raet

Project Manager Development

Amersfoort

Jun 2010 – Nov 2010

Setup the project to migrate to applications bought by Raet from PHP to .Net and integrating them in the Raet portal. Other responsibilities included the daily management of the development team and creating a roadmap for future product development after the migration was finished.

Raet Consultant

Amersfoort

May 2007 – Jun 2010

Advised customers on HR processes and how to best use Raet software. Configuration of Raet software for customers. Training users on how to use Raet software. Project management.

Developed a PHP application used for migrating and importing data in one of the payroll applications.

COURSES

Udacity Product Design

Prowareness Scrum Product Owner

In company training as Scrum Product Owner

Capgemini Academy Prince 2 Practitioner

CLU – University of Utrecht Didactic Skills

EDUCATION

Saxion Hogescholen Bachelor Business Administration

2002 - 2009 International Business and Management

Studies

Major in E-Business

SIDE PROJECTS

Dromotica

Dromotica enables users of the open source home automation system Domoticz to control their home from their Android phone. It adds geofencing and NFC control to the system.

Dromotica is available in the <u>Play store</u> and is installed on over 10000+ devices worldwide.

Tech stack: Java, REST Api, JSON

OTHER ACTIVITIES

Duikvereniging NoBaToWa President

Nov 2015 – present

Duikvereniging NoBaToWaGeneral Member of the board

Mar 2009 – Mar 2010

Stichting Brink21 Member of the board

2003 - 2005

LANGUAGES SPOKEN

Dutch Native speaker

English Fluent German Beginner

SKILLS MATRIX

Programming languages	1 (Novice)	2	3	4	5 (Expert)
PHP			X		
Node.JS			Λ	X	
Go		X		Λ	
Python	X	Λ			
Java (Android)	Λ	X			
HTML		Λ	X		
CSS3			X		
LESS			X		
		X	Λ		
C++ (Arduino)		Λ			
Frameworks					
Laravel				X	
Sails.JS				X	
Meteor			X		
jQuery				X	
Bootstrap				X	
Materialize CSS			X		
Databases & Datastores					
MySQL				X	
Postgresql		X		/1	
Elasticsearch		Λ	X		
MSSQL		X	Λ		
Redis		Λ	X		
Amazon RDS			71	X	
MongoDB			X	71	
Neo4J			X		
100 13			71		
Hosting & Servers					
Docker			X		
Amazon EC2				X	
Amazon S3				X	
Amazon SQS				X	
Amazon Cloudfront				X	
Amazon Route53				X	
Mesosphere			X		
Operating systems					
Ubuntu Linux				X	
OSX				X	
Windows				X	
··· ** ··*					
Servers					
Apache		X			
NGINX			X		
Testing					
Sinon		X			
Chai		X			
Mocha		X			
Other					
Other			37		
Bamboo			X		
Teamcity			X		

Man Juli		I	v	
Mandrill			X	
Transloadit			X	
Magento	X			
Haproxy		X		
Scrum			X	
Kanban			X	
Tools				
Git			X	
Android Studio			X	
Sublime Text			X	
Atom			X	
SourceTree			X	
Trello			X	
Grunt	X			
IntelliJ		X		